Get out of here. Quick.
Take precautions!
Hurry and go!
Hurry, or you'll all die.
Go!
Don't go in.
You'll die if you touch those things.
They won't touch us.
Don't go in.
Don't worry.
-Don't go in.
There's a stench of rotting flesh.
Shrimpie.
[Inside the Ming Dynasty Shipwreck]
Look, the ship's turned to stone.
The reef and the hull are stuck together.
We can barely see anything.
It really looks like a sunken ship
from the Ming Dynasty.
Stop analyzing.
It's surrounded by seawater.
It's been here too long
and could easily collapse.
Let's move quickly.
The bodies in these bags have all rotted.
Why did the ancient people
hang up these corpses?
Look here.
If I'm not mistaken,
they hung up the bodies
to collect bodily fluids
and nourish these plants.
A Ming Dynasty nautical chart.
No wonder these corpses rotted like that.
It might belong
to the crew from that time.
They probably hung
these body bags up, too.
[On the day of departure, the sea
and sky were clear, and the waters were calm]
[More than a hundred people aboard
attended to their duties in good order]
It also records a strange event.
[On the seventh day of the voyage,
strange things happened]
It says that when the ship set sail,
the crew suddenly began
to die mysteriously.
Each victim developed
red rashes across the body
and died as their flesh
gradually ulcerated.
As more and more people died,
the whole crew panicked.
What's wrong, Mr. San?
This ship...
This ship is haunted by water ghosts.
Water ghosts. The water ghosts are here!
The souls of those you sank into the sea
will be trapped upon the waters,
unable to return home.
So,
they turned into evil spirits
and came back
to the ship to claim our lives!
Mr. San, what should we do?
Hang up all the corpses—
trap the evil spirits inside the corpses.
Once we dock,
give them a proper burial.
Remember,
the feet of the corpses
must never touch the deck.
Black water dripped from these corpses,
which actually worsened the disaster.
[A few months later]
It must be that, back then,
someone on the ship
was poisoned by Twilight Grass.
Those poisoned people
were tainted with the seeds
of Twilight Grass.
After they died,
the seeds grew on their corpses.
Twilight Grass likes
a dark and humid environment,
and the cabin perfectly fits.
Day by day,
Twilight Grass spread throughout the ship,
causing tragedy for the whole ship.
This black bodily fluid
must contain Twilight Grass seeds.
Otherwise, there wouldn't be
so many of these plants.
This is the essence of this ship—
the concentrated bodily fluid
of those who died from poison.
What do you want to do?
Those bastards up there
definitely want this.
Such a dangerous thing—
how can we let it stay and harm the world?
Let me disinfect you.
Looks like you're enjoying it.
Really?
Is it that obvious?
You guys,
go help over there!
Hurry!
Go!
Yes, sir.
Adjutant Chen, what's wrong?
Why is it such a mess here?
You ordered us to blast the reef cave.
Now that the reef is blown open,
something came out.
Our men suffered heavy casualties.
Did Salty Zhang hurt you like this?
Who?
Salty Zhang.
Your lifelong nemesis.
Salty Zhang...
The Commander and I have worked hard
on this for so many years.
We can't let them take it away.
Even if I die,
I will get those seeds back for you.
Someone is coming.
I should have finished this kid
off just now.
What a mistake.
Burn all the evidence.
Don't let anyone go!
The only exit is blocked by them.
You want to use the bomb
to blow open the hull
and use the shockwave
to blast us into the sea?
You're crazy.
Let's try.
Leave it to fate.
Throw all the bombs over there!
Blow them up!
I didn't expect such heavy fire.
Can this thing
even hold up?
Do you want to go back to Xiacheng?
Nonsense. Of course, I do.
Okay.
What do you mean?
Zhang Hailou.
I don't want to go back there.
I have nothing left to hold me there.
You go back in my place.
Shrimpie,
can you stop—
Zhang Haixia, what are you doing?
Shrimpie,
are you crazy?
[Archives: The Nanyang Mystery]
[Episode 3]
Shrimpie.
Shrimpie, stay with me.
I'm taking you home.
Then have you ever thought about
the people around you?
You've had your fun,
but what about the rest of us?
Do you want to go back to Xiacheng?
Nonsense. Of course, I do.
I don't want to go back there.
I have nothing left to hold me there.
You go back in my place.
Zhang Haixia, what are you doing?
[A Hundred Flowers in Bloom]
[A dozen years ago]
[The Zhang Residence, Xiacheng]
Mentor.
Zhang Hailou,
what are you drawing?
A thrush. Looks like one, right?
Zhang Haixia,
what's wrong with your eyebrows?
Go wash off those eyebrows.
This is your true nature.
Your true nature is a snake.
A snake
will devour everything.
But you can't be blamed for this.
Luckily, you had dumb luck,
having Zhang Haixia by your side—
he will remind you.
Did you hear that?
Be nicer to me.
Help!
[Beilian Wharf]
Commander.
The ship departed
from Panhua Reef half a month ago
and just arrived at the port today.
This is a letter written by Adjutant Chen.
Dear Commander,
after ten years of wandering,
fortunately, I did not fail your trust.
I've obtained the Twilight Grass seeds,
completing your instructions.
Please be careful
of the Southern Archives under
the Maritime Supervisory Office.
The person I encountered at Panhua Reef
was Salty Zhang,
an agent from the Archives.
Additionally,
the Twilight Grass Poison has spread,
infecting all the soldiers in the fleet.
Everyone else has been eliminated.
The soldiers on the ship
must not be kept alive
to prevent future trouble.
Commander,
Adjutant Chen's body has stiffened.
We can't get the jar off.
What is the axe for?
Chop off his hand
and take the jar.
The so-called
[Mo Yungao, Leader
of the Mo Warlord Faction of Beilian]
Southern Archives
under the Nanyang
Maritime Supervisory Office—
investigate it thoroughly, okay?
After finding them,
[Lu Junxiang, Adjutant
in the Mo Warlord Faction of Beilian]
how should we deal with them?
In the letter, he said
that the man is called Salty Zhang.
His surname is Zhang.
A member of the Zhang family.
I have finally found you.
By any means necessary,
find everyone in the Archives for me.
[Mo Yungao's Special Train]
Commander.
I have investigated everywhere.
But didn't find
the so-called Southern Archives.
We caught some people
who are suspected members of the Archives.
Some of them revealed a few clues.
The Southern Archives
is an organization that specializes
in investigating mysterious incidents.
It originated
from an ancient Zhang family.
That family
is very mysterious
and has extraordinary power.
The leader
of the Archives
is Zhang Haiqi.
Zhang Haiqi.
In the Panhua Reef Case,
the advisor's prophecy
was almost fully realized.
The case ended
with two agents critically injured
and remains unresolved.
What they did not expect was that,
during their recovery,
the Balongzhou Branch
of the Southern Archives
was suddenly ordered
to suspend all operations.
All personnel were dismissed
and instructed to recover on their own.
[Notice of Closure—
Maritime Supervisory Office]
Zhang Hailou kept trying
to contact the headquarters,
but never received any reply.
Where have all the people
from the Archives gone?
Why didn't even Mentor respond?
[Balai Rainforest]
Time passed.
In the three years
since the Panhua Reef case,
members of the Southern Archives
in various branches
went missing one after another.
Zhang Haiqi,
the director of the Archives,
has been investigating it.
Who hung those bodies up?
I don't know.
It seems they offended someone
and were hung up in revenge.
They've been hanging for a long time.
I heard they were still alive
when they were just hung up.
Their screams could be heard every day.
Drive the car over.
Why did you kill the people
of the Archives?
Who are you?
Who betrayed the Archives?
You don't need to know.
You won't live anyway.
I won't let you die
without knowing the truth.
[Nanyang Maritime Supervisory Office]
[Nanyang Daily]
Are you still thinking about these things?
Over the years,
I've looked into many plants related
to Twilight Grass.
But later, I found out
that the last time Twilight Grass appeared
was in the late Ming Dynasty.
This grass, from root to seed,
is highly toxic.
The fact that we survived
is nothing short of a miracle.
It's been so long since this happened.
Is it meaningful
for you to think about it?
How is it?
Still no news from headquarters?
Not only no news,
but they haven't even paid us.
Do you think the Archives
will be disbanded?
If it is disbanded,
what are your plans?
I think
we need to go back to Xiacheng
to find Mentor as soon as possible.
If it weren't for me,
you could have gone back
to Xiacheng a long time ago.
Don't say that.
When we get back
to Xiacheng and find Mentor,
I'm sure she'll
be able to cure your leg.
Even if she can't,
you still have me.
I'll take care of you
till the day you die.
My leg
cannot be cured.
One day,
you will have to act on your own.
I won't be by your side.
No one will be watching over you.
I can just quit my job.
You are so capable.
It'd be a pity if you quit.
What's the use of being capable?
I made you end up like this.
Actually, it's not too late
for you to understand all this now.
You still have a long way to go.
You have to keep moving forward.
Just tell me what you want to say.
I'll listen.
When you encounter something
in the future,
you must stay calm.
Never act on impulse.
Think about
how it will affect the people around you.
Got it.
I'm sorry.
Look at this.
Do you like it?
No, thank you.
Newspaper! Newspaper!
Mysterious toxic plant spreads rapidly.
-Many people have died of poisoning in Xucheng!
-Kid.
I'll get a newspaper.
Newspaper! Newspaper!
Mysterious toxic plant spreads rapidly.
[Nanyang Daily]
Many people have died
of poisoning in Xucheng!
We've got business. Hurry.
Look at this.
Is it exactly what I thought?
We're out of money. Why are you
buying so many newspapers?
Didn't I pick up a bunch
of newspapers for you?
A bizarre disease suddenly
broke out in Xucheng.
Resembles...
[Resembles a dandelion]
A large number of red rashes
appear all over the body,
[It is highly lethal]
accompanied by ulceration.
[Some victims may die instantly]
Death occurs rapidly after inhalation.
Twilight Grass.
It's been three years.
We are the only two
who survived the Panhua Reef,
apart from those warlords.
I've been looking up information
on the Twilight Grass all these years,
but with no results.
Now it has finally appeared.
Those bastards are back.
What are they up to?
The Evil God case was connected
to the warlords, too.
Maybe these two things are related.
Forget it.
The Archives are gone.
Why should I investigate?
What does it have to do with me?
The shipping in Nanyang
is very developed now.
Thousands of people
pass through every dock every day.
If it really is the Twilight Grass,
those stamens,
filaments, and seeds
will be brought to various places.
They are all highly toxic
and will endanger ordinary people.
Although we haven't been paid
for a long time,
the Archives
still has a duty to issue warnings.
You don't want those people
to suffer, either, do you?
Why don't you go and take a look?
I'll be back quickly.
[The Xucheng Twilight Grass Poison Case]
Shrimpie.
We're here. Get down.
Wait here a minute.
I'll go get a seat for you.
What's going on?
Don't worry. She's not poisoned.
I waited for her
outside the city for three days.
She's already been disinfected
and bathed.
We're both familiar with this poison.
If she were poisoned,
ulceration would definitely appear
within three days.
Have a seat.
She's Zhang Haijiao.
Call him Uncle Shrimpie.
Uncle Shrimpie.
You named the younger generation
using characters from our own generation?
Mentor said
that those living abroad can take "Hai"
as their generation name
to signify their separation from home
and their wandering lives.
Are you thirsty?
Separation from home
and their wandering lives...
My name is Zhang Haixia.
"Xia," as in a wandering hero.
His name is Zhang Hailou.
"Lou," as in tower.
Listening to the spring rain
through the night in a little tower.
A wandering hero of Xianyang
for many years.
Is that a line of poetry?
I meant for you to fan her.
Fine.
To welcome Haijiao,
we are having hotpot today.
Thank you, Uncle Shrimpie.
These three villages
were the first places where Twilight Grass
spread simultaneously.
In there,
[When did they get poisoned?]
[July 2] [First Victim]
the first victims
all had boarded Nan'an
[The Nan'an]
from Xiacheng to Balai
in the first week of July.
I've checked the news in Xiacheng—
no one was poisoned by the Twilight Grass.
This means
these three people must
have been poisoned aboard the ship.
You can take a closer look
[Yeruicheng] [Yungangyi] [Langhuacheng]
at the locations of these villages.
[Balai] [Xucheng]
They are evenly
distributed around Xucheng.
[Yeruicheng] [Yungangyi] [Langhuacheng]
I think someone
deliberately found these three people
and had them carry Twilight Grass Poison
back to their villages at the same time,
so that the toxic weed could spread
as quickly as possible.
If this incident
was also the work of the warlord
who dug up the Twilight Grass back then,
their people are likely on Nan'an.
[When did they get poisoned?]
[July 2] [First Victim]
Since all clues now point to Nan'an,
should we get on the ship and investigate?
When will it dock again?
Next week.
The Nan'an heads to Xiacheng.
If you want to investigate,
you have to go the whole way
and get off at Xiacheng.
The tickets for Nan'an
are very expensive.
Even with a one-way steerage ticket,
our money is only enough for one.
And by the time you come back,
it will be a year later,
right?
You don't need to worry about that.
I've already thought about it.
If we sell this place,
we can buy two tickets
and go back to Xiacheng together.
And
we can return to Xiacheng
in the name of investigating a case.
That way, we definitely won't
be considered deserters.
Sell the Archives?
How could you come up with such an idea?
Why not?
Why don't you just sell me instead?
Hey, this place has
been abandoned for three years.
They are just worldly possessions.
We have to think
about the living first, right?
You go back.
Go back and check
why our salaries haven't arrived.
And visit Mentor while you're at it.
If the Southern Archives is gone,
don't come back.
Send me a telegram,
and we'll part ways.
Absolutely not.
We agreed to go back together.
It would be so awkward
if I went back alone.
And the money belongs to both of us.
You have a share.
I've made up my mind.
I'm not going back.
You go back for me.
There's no need
to waste your life here with me.
Forget it.
I'll investigate
those three villages first.
Maybe you're right.
This way, neither of us
has to go back to Xiacheng.
That's good.
Hailou,
you still have a long way to go.
You have to keep moving forward.
When we get back
to Xiacheng and find Mentor,
I'm sure she'll be able to cure your leg.
You've already switched sides?
Have you forgotten who brought you back?
Uncle Shrimpie said
you really want to go back to Xiacheng.
It's not easy to have something
you want to do in mind.
He envies you very much.
So you want to drive me away?
Didn't you say
you brought me back
just to serve Uncle Shrimpie
like my own father?
I will take good care of him.
You can leave without worrying about us.
Did Shrimpie Zhang teach you to say that?
This is also my own idea.
In the future, Uncle Shrimpie
and I will depend on each other.
We will work hard on our business.
When we save enough money,
we will come to Xiacheng
to reunite with you.
You can leave without worrying about us.
We won't die without you.
Zhang Haixia, what's the point of this?
You're not dead.
You were expelled from the Archives,
and you still have the nerve
to show up here?
Do I have to send you to prison,
or will you go on your own?
Don't act rashly.
Call him Mr. Zhang Ruipu.
According to seniority,
he is even Mentor's senior.
I heard you're looking
into the Twilight Grass.
So I came specifically to help.
Long time no see.
A master from the common folk?
Turns out you're actually poor.
Mr. Zhang, beat us
or kill us as you please.
Why mock us?
I just think your spirit is commendable.
So poor, yet you
still work for the Archives.
Actually, the first time
you appeared under that saline lake,
I had already known who you were.
But I felt that with your qualities,
you'd never catch me.
So I didn't eliminate you,
lest the Southern Archives
send some reliable people
and leave me no peace in Xucheng.
As a result,
living up to expectations,
you were even more incompetent
than I expected.
Actually, last time, we were
investigating the Evil God Case.
Tricking you was just a bonus.
By the way,
how much do you know
about this Twilight Grass Poison case?
Don't waste my time.
Zhang Hailou.
Twilight Grass hasn't appeared
for hundreds of years.
This time, it suddenly
broke out in Xucheng,
yet you came back alive
from a heap of corpses.
As far as I know,
only those who have been
exposed to Twilight Grass
can develop
an alkaloid barrier in their bodies.
How were you exposed to it?
Your brother-in-arms
was crippled because of you.
You've taken care of him until now...
Are you a bit tired of it?
If there's an accident,
for example,
I help you kill him,
would your life be a bit easier?
Since you were from the Archives,
you should know the rules of it.
The Southern Archives' rule
has always been:
what must not be said
will not be said,
even if one's closest kin dies right
before their eyes.
How can you threaten me with this?
You keep him.
I'm leaving.
Zhang Ruipu!
How touching.
I'm envious.
Then I suppose it's time
to start extracting answers.
Answer me,
or I start snapping his spine,
vertebrae by vertebrae.
For every minute you hesitate,
I'll crush another one.
Right now, his arms still have feeling.
In seven minutes,
other than his head...
No,
he'll only be able to move his head.